

# CHRISTOPHER WRAY

## Full Stack Engineer & Web Developer

Tepic, Nay.

chris@solmediaco.com

509 412 4220

After my wife and I got married in 2017, we ended up being sent back to Mexico because of my wife's tourist visa for the United States. We needed to wait in Mexico to get her Green Card. That is when I built my small business, Soltech, and started doing web design and development for companies in the United States and Mexico.

Over the past several years, I have learned so much here in Mexico and found out that I am super passionate about web design and development, software, and coding. I love to code, design websites in Webflow, and love helping solve problems.

Willing to relocate to: Tri-Cities, WA - -

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Full Stack Engineer/ Web Developer

Soltech Llc - Tepic, Nay.

October 2017 to Present

I started Soltech Llc to help small businesses market their brands online with better websites.

- Design and develop websites in Webflow to help clients easily manage content and for quickly updating designs.
- Developing applications in Laravel for security, architecture, and up to date PHP programming.
- Frontend interactions and website development with VueJs for client-side interactivity and state management.
- Provisioning servers and zero-downtime deployments on Digital Ocean, Heroku, Netlify, and other providers.
- Manage several websites with different Content Management Systems including WordPress, Webflow, Ecwid, and Shopify.
- Provide tech support for companies regarding DNS settings, email, Office 365 administration, website, and software architecture questions.

#### **Team Lead**

Garden Gate Nursery LLC - Pasco, WA

April 2011 to October 2017

- Responsible for running the planting and production team. Sped up processes greatly by streamlining day to day tasks and scheduling.
- Handled day-to-day operations and made sure tasks were completed in a timely manner while helping team members as

#### needed.

- Worked with nursery customer relationships and happiness ensuring customers were completely satisfied with the plants and service provided.
- Managed marketing, inventory management, pruning, irrigation, and order fulfillment.
- Set up safety procedures and Safety Data Sheets (SDS) for chemicals used. This included safety meetings, a safety procedure booklet, and notifying employees when chemicals were applied.

### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor's in Software Development**

Western Governors University
August 2020 to Present

### **Associate in Arts and Sciences**

Columbia Basin College - Pasco, WA 2011 to 2013

## High school or equivalent

Chiawana Senior High School - Pasco, WA June 2011

### **SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- Laravel
- HTML5 (2 years)
- · Customer Service (4 years)
- Front-End Development
- VueJs
- C++
- · Webflow (2 years)

## LINKS

https://chriswray.dev

https://dev.to/cwraytech

https://github.com/cwray-tech

https://solmediaco.com

### CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

## CompTIA A+

September 2020 to September 2023

## CompTIA Project+

October 2020 to October 2023

## **ASSESSMENTS**

# Data Analysis — Expert

November 2019

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data.

Full results: Expert

## **Problem Solving — Expert**

November 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to analyze relevant information when solving problems

Full results: Expert

## **Programming Fundamentals — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Designed by engineering managers and real-world employers, this test gives you hard data points to evaluate technical competency.

Full results: Highly Proficient

## **Customer Service — Highly Proficient**

June 2020

Identifying and resolving common customer issues.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## **Personal Blog**

https://chriswray.dev/posts

I publish articles on my website semi-regularly.

Dev.to

https://dev.to/cwraytech